{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following medium are used to differentiate the colonies of Vibrio cholerae and  V parahaemolyticus?", "opta": "Alkaline bile salt", "optb": "Thiosulphate-citrate-bile-sucrose", "optc": "MacConkey", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the followings can be used to differentiate between classical and El Tor biotypes of Vibrio cholerae?", "opta": "Sensitivity to Mukerjee's group IV phage", "optb": "Agglutination of fowl RBCs", "optc": "Sensitivity to polymyxin B", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following biotypes of Vibrio cholerae are prevalent in India?", "opta": "EI Tor", "optb": "Classical", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacteria is associated with food poisoning due to consumption of sea fish?", "opta": "Vibrio parahaemolyticus", "optb": "V alginolyticus", "optc": "V vulnificus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following conditions can be caused by Plesiomonas?", "opta": "Septicaemia", "optb": "Gastroenteritis", "optc": "Cellulites", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Acute diarrhoeal disease resembling cholera can be caused due to", "opta": "Aeromonas hydrophila", "optb": "Vibrio vulnificus", "optc": "V. alginolyticus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transport medium for Vibrio cholerae can be", "opta": "Venkatraman-Ramakrishnan medium", "optb": "Selenite F broth", "optc": "Tetrathionate broth", "optd": "Nutrient broth", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following does not cause wound infection following exposure to sea water or infected shellfish?", "opta": "Vibrio vulnificus", "optb": "V. alginolyticus", "optc": "V. cholerae", "optd": "Aeromonas", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The test(s) used for the assay of cholera toxin is/are", "opta": "Radioimmunoassay", "optb": "Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay", "optc": "Morphological changes in Chinese hamster ovary cells", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The DNA coding for the production of cholera toxin in Vibrio cholerae is on the", "opta": "phage", "optb": "plasmid", "optc": "chromosome", "optd": "transposon", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The halophilic bacteria is/are", "opta": "V. alginolyticus", "optb": "V. vulnificus", "optc": "Vibrio parahaemolyticus", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following toxin resembles cholera toxin?", "opta": "Stable toxin of E. coli", "optb": "Diphtheria toxin", "optc": "Labile toxin of Escherichia coli", "optd": "Tetanus toxin", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}